Okay, so I have some bad news.
Programming just like everything else is
bound by the laws of physics, which
means we are also bound by the speed of
light. We cannot send information or
process pull in information any faster
than the speed of light. Because the
speed of light is not instantaneous, it
means that if we want to send something
over a short distance, it takes a
shorter time than if we want to send
something over a long distance. Um, that
variation can cause us problems when we
are trying to access data outside of our
computer. when our computer is accessing
a variable from memory, it's only going
to a very short distance inside the
computer from the processor to the RAM.
Um, but when you're trying to access
something that's not in memory, it can
take longer. For example, maybe it's
going from your computer to another
computer on your network. Or if you're
requesting something from out on the
internet, then it has to go from your
computer out of your network, probably
over multiple other networks, to that
other computer, and then back to your
computer. And all of that takes time.
when you're coding, you have to think
about that. So sometimes these
operations take so long that our options
are to either freeze the screen or shift
stuff to the background while we wait
for the request to process. In order to
demonstrate that, I do need to show you
two functions. We'll use these two
functions to simulate the passage of
time and then a delay. So the first is
called set timeout and the second is
called set interval.